Guide to the Donald Davie Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Correspondence, 1957-1995; Series I; 3.2; (8 boxes)
  - Routledge & Kegan Paul, 1980, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 277)
  - Royal Society of Literature (Great Britain), 1982 Apr 15 (Box 6, Folder 278)
  - Rudolf, Anthony, n.y. Oct 25 (Box 6, Folder 279)
  - "S" general, 1971-95 (Box 6, Folder 280-281)
  - Sawyer, John F., 1988 Feb 4 (Box 6, Folder 282)
    Encloses copy of letter from Alan McDonald dated 1988 Jan 26.
  - Schirmer, Gregory A., 1983 Oct 3 (Box 6, Folder 283)
  - Schmidt, Michael, 1972-95 (Box 6, Folder 284-293)
  - Scripsi (Parkville, Victoria), 1982-89 (Box 6, Folder 294)
  - Servotte, Herman, 1984 Sep 12 (Box 6, Folder 295)
  - Seth, Vikram, 1982, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 296)
  - Shankman, Steven, 1984 Oct 31 (Box 6, Folder 297)
  - Shapiro, Alan, 1978-95, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 298-300)
  - Siegelman, Ellen
  - Sisson, C. H., 1974-93 (Box 7, Folder 301-303)
  - Small, Christopher, 1981 Aug 22 (Box 7, Folder 304)
  - Southwest Review, 1995 Feb 10 (Box 7, Folder 305)
  - Spender, Stephen, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 306)
  - Stead, Karl, 1982-84 (Box 7, Folder 307)
  - Stegner, Wallace Earle, 1972-87 (Box 7, Folder 308)
  - Steiner, George, 1974-93 (Box 7, Folder 309)
  - Stock, Noel, 1974, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 310)
  - Stoenescu, Stefan, 1982-92 (Box 7, Folder 311)
  - Stokes, Adrian Durham
    See: Richard Read, box 6, folder 264
  - Styan, J. L., 1990 Dec 2 (Box 7, Folder 312)
  - Sullivan, Walter, 1989-94 (Box 7, Folder 313)
  - Super, R. H., 1986 Oct 20 (Box 7, Folder 314)
  - Swarbrick, Alan, 1979-84 (Box 7, Folder 315)
  - Sykes, Robert, 1995 Feb 20 (Box 7, Folder 316)
  - "T" general, 1978-90 (Box 7, Folder 317)
  - Taylor, Dennis, 1994 Sep 21 (Box 7, Folder 318)
  - Tennyson, G. B., 1979, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 319)
  - Thomas, R. S., [1971 Apr 8] (Box 7, Folder 320)
  - Thomas, Ray, 1990-94 (Box 7, Folder 321)
  - Thompson, E. P., [1978] May 21 (Box 7, Folder 322)
  - Tibble, Anne Northgrave, 1974 Apr 12 (Box 7, Folder 323)
  - The Times Literary Supplement, 1969 Jun 24 (Box 7, Folder 324)
  - Torchiana, Donald T.
  - Trachtenberg, Alan, 1976 Jan 20 (Box 7, Folder 325)
  - Trimpi, Helen P., 1984 Sep 1 (Box 7, Folder 326)
  - Turco, Lewis, 1987 Jul 29 (Box 7, Folder 327)
  - Turnbull, Gael, 1966 May 11 (Box 7, Folder 328)
  - University of Chicago Press, 1990-91 (Box 7, Folder 329)
  - University of Essex. Library, 1981, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 330)
  - University of Exeter, 1983, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 331)
  - University of North Carolina Press, 1988 Feb 2 (Box 7, Folder 332)
  - University of Tasmania. Library, 1975 Feb 10 (Box 7, Folder 333)
  - University of the South, 1982 Mar 1 (Box 7, Folder 334)
  - Unterecker, John Eugene
    See: Yeats International Summer School, box 29, folders 736-741
  - "V" general, 1988, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 335)
  - Vendler, Helen Hennessy, [1988 Apr] (Box 7, Folder 336)
  - Viking Press, 1980 Mar 11 (Box 7, Folder 337)
  - Von Hallberg, Robert, 1979-93 (Box 7, Folder 338)
  - "W" general, 1969-95 (Box 7, Folder 339)
  - Wainwright, Geoffrey, 1982 Sep 10 (Box 7, Folder 340)
  - Warren, Robert Penn, 1980 Jul 21 (Box 7, Folder 341)
  - Warren, Rosanna, 1982-94, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 342-343)
  - Warshaw, Howard, 1977, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 344)
    Encloses copies of letters to Faber and Faber and photo of mural by Warshaw.
  - Waterman, Andrew, 1981, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 345)
  - Watt, Ian P., 1986-94 (Box 8, Folder 346)
  - Weatherby, Harold L., 1982-94 (Box 8, Folder 347)
  - Weiss, Theodore Russell, 1976 Apr 29 (Box 8, Folder 348)
  - Wells, Robert, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 349)
  - Whigham, Peter, 1983-86 (Box 8, Folder 350)
  - Wieseltier, Leon
    See: The New Republic, box 5, folder 219
  - Wilkinson, Oliver Marlow, 1986-95 (Box 8, Folder 351)
  - Williams, Jonathan, 1982 (Box 8, Folder 352)
  - Wilmer, Clive, 1982-95 (Box 8, Folder 353-356)
  - Wilner, Eleanor, 1993 Jan 2 (Box 8, Folder 357)
  - Wiltshire, Susan Ford, 1982 Sep 6 (Box 8, Folder 358)
  - Winters, Janet
    See: Janet Lewis, box 4, folders 181-183
  - Winters, Arthur
    See: Yvor Winters, box 8, folder 359
  - Winters, Yvor, 1949-66 (Box 8, Folder 359)
    Letters from 1949-51, 1958 Jun 16, 1958 Dec 26, and 1966 Sep 16 are photocopies. Letter dated 1949 Dec 9 includes explanatory annotation by DD. Includes list of quotations from Winters's letters to DD.
  - Wintle, Frank, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 360)
  - Wood, Richard Clement, 1980-94, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 361-362)
  - Wright, Charles, 1982 Sep 16 (Box 8, Folder 363)
  - Wright, David, 1993 Jan 5 (Box 8, Folder 364)
  - "Y" general, 1993 Oct 12 (Box 8, Folder 365)
  - Yeats International Summer School, 1982-88, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 366-368)
  - Yorkshire Arts Association, 1988 Jul 28 (Box 8, Folder 369)
  - Young, Alan, 1978 (Box 8, Folder 370)
  - Zach, Nathan, 1968-71 (Box 8, Folder 371)
  - Zubrzycki, Jerzy, 1995 Jan 18 (Box 8, Folder 372)
  - Unidentified, 1985, 1990, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 373)
- Writings, 1946-1995; Series II; 4; (11 boxes)
  Series II, Writings, is organized into seven subseries: Articles, Books, Lectures, Poems, Reviews, Other Writings, and Writings of Others. Each subseries is arranged alphabetically.
  - ARTICLES
    - "Americans in Venice (Out of Season)," holograph and typescript, corrected (Box 9, Folder 374)
    - "Andrea del Sarto," typescript, corrected (Box 9, Folder 375)
    - "Arthur Yvor Winters (1900-1968)," typescript, corrected (photocopy), [1987] (Box 9, Folder 376)
    - "Artistry and Artifice in the Anglo-American Lyric," typescript, corrected (Box 9, Folder 377)
    - "Attending to Landor," typescript, corrected, [1984] (Box 9, Folder 378)
    - "Books and the Sun Belt," typescript (photocopy) (Box 9, Folder 379)
    - "Bunting's Reputation in the 1980s," typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 380)
    - "Chapters from a Literary Life," holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 381)
    - "The Critical Principles of William Cowper," printed version (photocopy), n.d. (Box 9, Folder 382)
    - "Dissent and Individualism," typescript, corrected (Box 9, Folder 383)
      See also: Books, Dissentient Voice: The Ward-Phillips Lectures for 1980 with Some Related Pieces, box 10, folders 436-442
      See also: Books, "Named in the Ancient House: Studies in Religious Dissent," box 11, folders 461-463
    - "Dramatic Poetry: Dryden's Conversation-Piece," printed version (photocopy), n.d. (Box 9, Folder 384)
    - "Eliot in One Poet's Life"
      - Page proof, n.d.
      - Printed version, Mosaic, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 385)
    - [An Englishman in Ireland], typescript, corrected (photocopy) (Box 9, Folder 386)
    - "Events and Spaces," typescript, corrected (Box 9, Folder 387)
    - "Ezra Among the Edwardians," typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 388)
    - "F. W. Bateson: In Memoriam," typescript, corrected (photocopy), n.d. (Box 9, Folder 389)
    - [Fallon, Padraic], typescript, corrected (fragment), n.d. (Box 9, Folder 390)
    - "Fiesole," typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 391)
    - "George Orwell's 1984 ," typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 392)
    - "God in Recent Poetry"
      See also: Other Writings, [Response to Richard Caddel and Peter Makin], box 19, folder 622
      - Proof, corrected, 1986
      - Clipping of printed version, The Times Literary Supplement, 1986 May 23 (Box 9, Folder 393)
    - "Homage to Cowper," typescript, corrected (photocopy), n.d. (Box 9, Folder 394)
    - "Introducing Aesthetes," typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 395)
    - "Landscape in British Literature, 1850 to the Present," typescript carbon, corrected (Box 9, Folder 396)
    - "Letter from England," holograph, corrected, [1977] (Box 9, Folder 397)
    - "The Life and Times of Ezra Pound," typescript, corrected (Box 9, Folder 398)
    - "Literature and Morality," typescript, corrected (Box 9, Folder 399)
    - "The Long Way Round to Italy," typescript, corrected (Box 9, Folder 400)
    - "Looking at Buildings," typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 401)
    - "Looking at Sculpture," typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 402)
    - "Lorine Niedecker: Lyric Minimum and Epic Scope," typescript and holograph, corrected (Box 9, Folder 403)
    - "The Meaning of a Cypress," typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 404)
    - "The Morning After the Revolution," proof, corrected, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 405)
    - "My Cambridge," printed version (photocopy), My Cambridge edited by Ronald Hayman, 1977, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 406)
    - "The Mysterious Allen Upward," typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 407)
    - "The Nonconformist Contribution to English Culture," printed version, The Times Literary Supplement, 1976 Nov 19 (Box 9, Folder 408)
    - "Nonconformist Poetics: A Response to Daniel Jenkins"
      - Typescript, corrected, [1983] (Box 9, Folder 409)
      - Printed version (photocopy), Journal of Literature & Theology (1988 Sep), n.d. (Box 9, Folder 409)
    - "On Being Literary," typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 410)
    - "Pasternak, Dr. Zhivago, and John Bayley," typescript (photocopy), corrected (Box 9, Folder 411)
    - "Peter Dale's Villon," typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 412)
    - "The Poems of Alexander Hume (?1557-1609), typescript, corrected (Box 9, Folder 413)
    - "The Poetry of the Metrical Psalm"
      See: Books, The Psalms in English, box 12, folders 475-481
    - "Presences and Antiquities," typescript, corrected (Box 9, Folder 414)
    - "R. S. Thomas's Poetry of the Church in Wales," typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 415)
    - "A Reading of 'The Ocean's Love to Cynthia,'" printed version (photocopy), n.d. (Box 9, Folder 416)
    - "A Rejoinder to Jon Silkin," typescript (mimeograph), corrected (Box 9, Folder 417)
    - "Remembering Russia"
      See: Books, These the Companions: Recollections, box 13, folders 493-500
    - "The Rhetoric of Emotion," proof, corrected, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 418)
    - "Siena," holograph and typescript, corrected (Box 9, Folder 419)
    - "Singing the Praises of Gloucester," clipping of printed version, 1990 Sep 1 (Box 9, Folder 420)
    - "Some Audibility Gaps," proof, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 421)
    - "Suburban Ebenezers," typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 422)
    - "Virgil," holograph, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 423)
    - "Virgil's Presence in Ezra Pound and Others"
      - Typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 424)
      - Typescript, corrected (photocopy), n.d. (Box 9, Folder 424)
    - "Yvor Winters," typescript (mimeograph), n.d. (Box 9, Folder 425)
  - BOOKS
    - Brides of Reason. Clippings of reviews, 1955-67, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 426)
    - Collected Poems
      - Table of contents, possibly for Collected Poems, draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 427)
      - Mailing list, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 428)
        List also serves for Slavic Excursions.
      - Clippings of reviews, 1990-92, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 429-431)
        See also: Slavic Excursions: Essays on Russian and Polish Literature, box 13, folder 491
    - Collected Poems, 1970-1983. Clippings of reviews, 1984 (Box 10, Folder 432)
    - Czeslaw Milosz and the Insufficiency of Lyric
      - Research materials, 1983-84 (Box 10, Folder 433)
      - Draft, typescript (Box 10, Folder 434-435)
      - Proof, corrected, n.d.
    - Dissentient Voice: The Ward-Phillips Lectures for 1980 with Some Related Pieces
      See also: "Named in the Ancient House: Studies in Religious Dissent," box 11, folders 461-463
      - Early draft, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 436-437)
      - Later draft, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 438-441)
      - Proof of jacket cover, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 442)
    - The Eighteenth-Century Hymn in England
      - Front page, draft, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 443)
      - Photographs, 1992, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 444)
      - Clippings of reviews, 1994 (Box 10, Folder 445)
    - Essex Poems, 1963-67, typescript and holograph, corrected (Box 10, Folder 446)
    - Events and Wisdoms: Poems, 1957-1963. Clippings of reviews, 1964-66 (Box 11, Folder 447)
    - Ezra Pound. Clippings of reviews, [1976] (Box 11, Folder 448)
    - Ezra Pound: Poet As Sculptor. Clippings of reviews, 1965-67, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 449)
    - The Forests of Lithuania: A Poem. Clippings of reviews, 1959-60, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 450)
    - A Gathered Church: The Literature of the English Dissenting Interest, 1700-1930
      - Research materials, 1964-75, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 451-452)
      - Photographs, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 453-455)
      - Clippings of reviews, 1978-80 (Box 11, Folder 456)
    - The Heyday of Sir Walter Scott. Clippings of reviews, 1961, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 457)
    - In the Stopping Train and Other Poems
      - Table of contents, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 458)
      - Clippings of reviews, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 459)
    - Kenneth Allott and the Thirties, typescript, corrected (Box 11, Folder 460)
    - "Named in the Ancient House: Studies in Religious Dissent," typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 461-463)
      See also: Dissentient Voice: The Ward-Phillips Lectures for 1980 with Some Related Pieces, box 10, folders 436-442
    - The New Oxford Book of Christian Verse, typescript, corrected, 1979 Aug 5 (Box 11, Folder 464-468)
    - "Pasternak: Translations and Imitations," draft, typescript, corrected (Box 12, Folder 469)
    - Poems and Melodramas. "Seven Melodramas," typescript, corrected (Box 12, Folder 470-471)
    - The Poems of Dr. Zhivago. Clippings of reviews, 1965-66, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 472)
    - The Poet in the Imaginary Museum: Essays of Two Decades. Clippings of reviews, 1978 (Box 12, Folder 473)
    - Pound. Clippings of reviews, 1975, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 474)
    - The Psalms in English
      - Research materials, 1992-95, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 475-477)
        Includes letters from Gerald Hammond, 1992 Nov 19, and Jerzy Zubrzycki, 1995 Feb 3.
      - Drafts, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 478-481)
    - Purity of Diction in English Verse, typescript carbon, corrected, in volume, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 482)
      Marked: "Early discarded draft."
    - "A Reading of Graves," table of contents, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 483)
    - Russian Literature and Modern English Fiction: A Collection of Critical Essays. Clippings of reviews, 1965-67 (Box 12, Folder 484)
    - Selected Poems, table of contents, typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 485)
    - The Shires
      - Table of contents, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 486)
      - Draft, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 487)
      - Galley proof, corrected, n.d.
      - Proof, corrected, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 488-489)
    - Slavic Excursions: Essays on Russian and Polish Literature
      - "Foreword," typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 490)
      - Mailing list
        See: Collected Poems, box 10, folder 428
      - Clippings of reviews, 1991-92, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 491)
    - Studies in Ezra Pound. Clippings of reviews, 1991-92, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 492)
    - These the Companions: Recollections
      See also: Series III, box 26, folder 702
      - "Remembering Russia," typescript carbon, [ca. 1946] (Box 13, Folder 493-494)
      - Draft, typescript (photocopy), corrected, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 495-496)
      - Page proof, spiral bound (Box 13, Folder 497)
      - Proof of jacket cover (2 copies), n.d. (Box 13, Folder 498)
      - Clippings of reviews, 1982-83, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 499-500)
    - Thomas Hardy and British Poetry
      - Draft, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 501-503)
      - Clippings of reviews, 1973 (Box 14, Folder 504)
    - "Three Analogies for Poetry," typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 505-506)
    - Three for Water-Music
      - Typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 507)
      - Typescript (mimeograph) (2 copies), n.d. (Box 14, Folder 507)
    - To Scorch or Freeze: Poems About the Sacred
      - Draft, typescript and typescript, corrected (photocopy) (Box 14, Folder 508)
      - Reader's report by Alan Shapiro, typescript (photocopy), n.d. (Box 14, Folder 509)
      - Clippings of reviews, 1988-90, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 510)
    - Trying to Explain
      - Table of contents, holograph, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 511)
      - Draft, typescript, corrected (photocopy), n.d. (Box 14, Folder 512-514)
      - Clippings of reviews, 1980 (Box 14, Folder 515)
    - Under Briggflatts: A History of Poetry in Great Britain, 1960-1988. Clippings of reviews, 1989-91, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 516-518)
    - A Winter Talent, and Other Poems. Clippings of reviews, 1957-58, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 519)
  - LECTURES
    - "Anglican Eliot," typescript (mimeograph), corrected, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 520)
      At English Institute.
    - "Artistry and Artifice in the Anglo-American Lyric," typescript, corrected, 1985 May (Box 15, Folder 521)
      To French teachers of English in Caen (France).
    - "The Direction and Purpose of Literary Criticism," holograph, corrected, 1971 May 5 (Box 15, Folder 522)
      At Review Club of Stanford University, Department of English.
    - "Dissent in the Present Century," clipping (photocopy) of printed version, The Times Literary Supplement (1976 Dec 3), annotated, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 523)
      Seventh of Clark Lectures at Trinity College (University of Cambridge).
    - "Edward Taylor and Isaac Watts," typescript (mimeograph), corrected, 1976 Jan 19 (Box 15, Folder 524)
      In New Haven.
    - "An English Poet's Response to Polish Poetry," notes, holograph, 1989 May 17 (Box 15, Folder 525)
      At University of London, School of Slavonic and East European Studies. With flyer and note from Keith Swords.
    - "Evangelical Poetry," typescript, corrected, 1992 Apr 5 (Box 15, Folder 526)
      To Phi Beta Kappa, Alpha of Tennessee, Vanderbilt University.
    - "Idiom and Jargon in Contemporary Literary Criticism," typescript, corrected, 1984 Jun 8 (Box 15, Folder 527)
      The Faculty Lecture at University of Exeter.
    - "Kenneth Allott and the Thirties," printed version, The Times Literary Supplement, 1980 Mar 7 (Box 15, Folder 528)
      Kenneth Allott Lecture at the University of Liverpool.
    - "Matthew Arnold and the Decline of Romanticism," typescript, corrected (Box 15, Folder 529)
    - "The Modern Movement," typescript and, holograph, corrected, 1971 Nov 18 (Box 15, Folder 530)
      At conference on the modern movement in literature, Toledo Museum of Art.
    - "Modernism in Poetry, and Post-Modernism," typescript, 1982 Mar 17 (Box 15, Folder 531)
      At Hofstra University.
    - "Old Dissent, 1700-1740," printed version, The Times Literary Supplement, 1976 Nov 26 (Box 15, Folder 532)
      Second of Clark Lectures at Trinity College (University of Cambridge).
    - "On the Lapidary Effect in Poetry," typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 533)
      Annotated by DD: "Possibly inaugural lecture for Sligo."
    - "Patriotism: Constraint or Incentive?," typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 534)
    - "The Persistent Alternative: Cassity, Pinsky, Others," typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 535)
    - "Personification," typescript and holograph, corrected (Box 15, Folder 536)
      At Princeton University.
    - [Poetry and music], typescript and holograph, corrected (Box 15, Folder 537)
    - "Political Consciousness," typescript, corrected, [1969 or 70] (Box 15, Folder 538)
      At Stanford University.
    - "The Rudiments of Verse"
      In Manchester.
      - Holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 539)
      - Typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 539)
    - "Santa Maria dei Miracoli," holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 540)
    - "Shakespeare and the Practising Poet Today"
      - Early draft, typescript and holograph, corrected (Box 15, Folder 541)
      - Later draft, typescript, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 541)
    - "Sidney Godolphin," holograph, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 542)
      "A talk for broadcasting."
    - [Townscape], typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 543)
      Annotated "Toxteth."
    - "A Tribute to Allen Tate," typescript, corrected, [1979] (Box 15, Folder 544)
    - "The Wild Swans at Coole," holograph, corrected, 1984 (Box 15, Folder 545)
      At Yeats International Summer School.
    - "Yvor Winters and the History of Ideas," typescript, corrected (mimeograph), [1979] (Box 15, Folder 546)
  - POEMS
    - "A," holograph and typescript, corrected (Box 16, Folder 547)
    - "B," holograph and typescript, corrected (Box 16, Folder 548)
    - "C," holograph and typescript, corrected (Box 16, Folder 549)
    - "D," holograph and typescript, corrected (Box 16, Folder 550)
    - "E," holograph and typescript, corrected, 1965, 1980, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 551-552)
    - "F-H," holograph and typescript, corrected, 1977, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 553)
    - "I-K," holograph and typescript, corrected, 1973, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 554)
    - "L-M," holograph and typescript, corrected, 1981, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 555)
    - "N-O," holograph and typescript, corrected (Box 16, Folder 556)
    - "P," holograph and typescript, corrected (Box 16, Folder 557-558)
    - "R," holograph and typescript, corrected, 1981, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 559)
    - "S," holograph and typescript, corrected, 1978, 1981, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 560-561)
    - "T," holograph and typescript, corrected (Box 16, Folder 562-563)
    - "V-Y," holograph and typescript, corrected (Box 17, Folder 564)
    - Untitled poems, drafts, holograph and typescript, corrected, 1980, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 565)
    - "Cuttings of Donald Davie's Published Poems," scrapbook, 1955-67 (Box 17, Folder 566)
  - REVIEWS
    - "After Sedley, After Pound," clipping (photocopy) of printed version, The Nation (1965 Nov 1) (Box 17, Folder 567)
      Review of All the Collected Short Poems, 1923-1958 by Louis Zukofsky.
    - "Against Rule and Compass"
      Review of George Crabbe: The Complete Poetical Works edited by Norma Dalrymple-Champneys and Arthur Pollard. Typescript titled "A Luckier Chatterton."
      - Typescript, corrected, [1988] (Box 17, Folder 568)
      - Clipping of printed version, The Times Literary Supplement, 1988 Sep 30 (Box 17, Folder 568)
    - "All of a Minor Classic"
      Review of Collected Poems of Thomas Parnell edited by Claude Rawson and F. P. Lock.
      - Typescript, corrected, [1989] (Box 17, Folder 569)
      - Clipping of printed version, The Times Literary Supplement, 1989 Dec 8 (Box 17, Folder 569)
    - Andrade, Carlos Drummond de. The Minus Sign: Selected Poems, typescript, corrected, [1980] (Box 17, Folder 570)
    - Bacigalupo, Massimo. The Formed Trace: The Later Poetry of Ezra Pound
      - Typescript, corrected (photocopy), [1980] (Box 17, Folder 571)
      - Typescript carbon, corrected, [1980] (Box 17, Folder 571)
    - "A Bee in His Sonnet"
      Review of Collected Poems, 1937-1971, by John Berryman edited by Charles Thornbury.
      - Typescript, corrected, [1989] (Box 17, Folder 572)
      - Printed version, The New Republic, 1989 Oct 23 (Box 17, Folder 572)
    - "Bloom's Bible," clipping of printed version, London Review of Books, 1991 Jun 13 (Box 17, Folder 573)
      Review of The Book of J translated by David Rosenberg and interpreted by Harold Bloom.
    - "Certainties," proof, corrected, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 574)
      Review of In Defence of the Imagination by Helen Gardner.
    - Cragg, Gerald R. The Works of John Wesley, Vol. II, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 575)
    - Crozier, Andrew and Tim Longville, editors. A Various Art, clipping of printed version, Poetry Nation Review (Box 17, Folder 576)
    - "A Demurral," printed version, The New Republic, 1987 Apr 20 (Box 17, Folder 577)